<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinay Hiremath</title>
    <link>http://www.vinayh.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vinay Hiremath</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 17:02:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.vinayh.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to backend web dev with Clojure [incomplete]</title>
      <link>http://www.vinayh.com/post/intro-clojure-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 17:02:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vinayh.com/post/intro-clojure-web/</guid>
      <description>(This tutorial was first given as a talk at a Michigan Hackers event on 2015-07-23. See my slides here. I have explained the first portion of the content here in more depth.)
I will start by talking about some basics of Clojure, then move onto explaining the fundamental purpose of a backend in web development, and finish with a demo of a simple web app (with complete code) that you can deploy to Heroku with a one-click button or try out on another platform of your choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://www.vinayh.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 15:28:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vinayh.com/license/</guid>
      <description>All non-code blog content is licensed under Creative Commons BY-NC-SA.
All source code files and snippets on this website are licensed under GPL v3.0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git hook to deploy static sites to S3</title>
      <link>http://www.vinayh.com/post/git-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 14:49:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vinayh.com/post/git-hooks/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly simple process to setup S3 syncing with a static site generator with source that you sync using Git. This will allow you to track revision history on your actual writing of posts, etc. while having the generated site automatically deployed on S3 on each push.
All you really need is:
 A way to upload a folder to S3 (I use the excellent s3cmd) A hook that triggers the upload on every git push  For example, if your static site generator is hugo, with destination dir public (like Hugo by default) and your S3 bucket is called &amp;lt;example_bucket&amp;gt;, create a new shell script called pre-push in the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.vinayh.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 11:06:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.vinayh.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! I am currently a fourth-year (in fall 2016) undergraduate student at the University of Michigan dual-majoring in Computer Science and Cognitive Science with a minor in Mathematics.
Please peruse my homepage for more details or to get in touch!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>