<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinay Hiremath</title>
    <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vinay Hiremath</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 22:38:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vinayh.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-03-23</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/daily/2020-03-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 23:33:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/daily/2020-03-23/</guid>
      <description>What is pride? I was in a conversation some few weeks ago with a friend in which they claimed to feel pride because of the country they were from, in contrast to many other places which handled the issue in question differently. At the time, this seemed like a normal turn of conversation, as expressing national pride is anything but uncommon. Later on, however, I started to wonder what this actually implied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-03-22</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/daily/2020-03-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 16:32:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/daily/2020-03-22/</guid>
      <description>I started this daily notes sub-blog to have a more frictionless way to post daily thoughts without the commitment of composing a full blog post. The #100Days challenge which requires writing and publishing a post every day for a hundred consecutive days seemed like an appropriate endeavor, particularly in this time of self-quarantining due to the coronavirus which necessitates more solitary activities. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the implications of obligating oneself to capture a fleeting thought and develop it into a coherent narrative, every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belonging</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/belonging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 21:48:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/belonging/</guid>
      <description>Taking a moment to reflect on the value of feeling like you belong and are accepted for who you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure web dev</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/clojure-web-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 17:02:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/clojure-web-dev/</guid>
      <description>A tutorial to get beginners to Clojure or web development acquainted with using Compojure and Heroku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git hook for static sites hosted on S3</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/s3-git-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 14:49:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/post/s3-git-hook/</guid>
      <description>A simple hook to sync a static site (generated, in this case) to AWS S3 with every Git push.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://vinayh.com/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 22:38:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinayh.com/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>A little bit about me. Feel free to visit the main site for a little bit more about me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>